Okay,
and once I know all the transcriptions
Yeah.
coming through,
then we're going to get started. Cool,
right.
We're going to run through this here,
right?
So I'm just going to open up the Earth
Kings Repo Vault here now as well.
And what we're going to run through is
the open questions that we have.
Oh yeah.
So what I was thinking was looking at the,
we've got like the kind of different 16
different possible characters you could
play.
Then we've got the world building as well
and different questions to answer,
Yeah.
that sort of thing.
So that line up with what you were saying
The.
as well.
So in the background as I'm just going to
swap this to the,
Earth Kings, right?
Where is this guy here?
What's up?
Whenever that loads up, got stuff,
kind of remind me getting rid of this
here.
Another docs.
Plainly what is left to the side.
Question book, right?
But this is...
But we still need to answer.
Okay.
Right,
his voice notes and we fill out the stuff.
So what's been answered so far?
World building answers.
Just talk one to three sentences. Perfect.
How to read the tables.
Yeah.
Just checking all these questions first.
Right, there's absolutely loads of them.
So we're going to,
let's just quickly see what's up here now.
Okay, right.
So I'm just going to put a little marker
here now.
So this is going to be the start of the
voice notes for me and the other
co-founder are going to be answering the
questions here. So say ID if you can,
yeah, we'll try say that.
So you and you actually answered a lot of
these questions already, didn't you?
Yeah.
And yeah, okay, cool. So part 0 frame,
what is the world about? Oh,
this is just breaking this down. Right,
okay. What's the world about? Skyland,
weather, making gates, death, minds,
knowledge, the grammar.
I think.
that a lot of these questions could be
kind of difficult to run through and
maybe might be important to us.
But I think that this...
The 16 characters could be good to run
through. Kind of different ideas. Yeah,
Yeah, let's do it.
we do that.
Do that.
And stuff, so VII.
Just because we don't want to be.
just world building forever like.
So this will be kind of like the types of
Yeah.
characters we want.
And the way it's going to do is it's
Yeah.
actually going to fit the character type
to the MBTI, the Miles Briggs test.
You ever do that?
No.
I'll just show you what it is for MBIT
personality test.
So this is my idea that I was like, right,
we're going to give them kind of a
personality based off the personality
test.
OK.
And this will decide then what they what
they do so we can have certain bad guys
and stuff, bad guys, good guys,
all that kind of stuff.
So open image and new tab, let's try this.
The.
This guy's back again,
throw him over there, so...
It's kind of like innovative, inventive,
enthusiastic, playful, outgoing,
responsible.
That's a tough one to actually understand
a better example here.
Nice one there.
Yeah, this is probably a better one here.
So, this is what it is, so...
The guys are going to be like this,
the architect, the logician,
the commander, the debater,
and this is what they usually behave like.
And the diplomats, they're like advocates,
you got like different healers down here,
Mhm.
campaigner,
they choose like diplomacy over action,
sentinels, these are like your paladins.
Healers.
Fact-minded,
like kind of looking after themselves,
kind of this explorers as your type
adventures.
entrepreneurs, entertainers, like bars,
all this kind of kind of virtuoso.
So you have all the kind of different
types of people is the idea,
Mhm.
is that each one tends to.
And so what we're going to do is after we
decide on what these 16 characters do or
just how many storylines we want,
it'll actually find which
personality tests they might be best
suited for.
So if we start talking about different
things we want to interest in,
like for example,
I'd love if there was a mage that was
just tiny,
like he's just really small and he just,
he's not able to walk.
properly so he needs someone else to
carry him to walk and because that then
Mhm.
like he's a lot more stronger but it's
kind of he's held back by that stuff and
I'd love to see like how he interacts
with people as well.
for kind of like, you know,
disgusting because they might look down
on him a little bit,
but I think he could be a cool kind of
character.
Yeah, he could.
Could be,
so I think these are the questions here.
Yeah, so I guess...
Can you see this stuff here?
Yes, I can.
that stuff. So what is their name?
So what could be cool kind of names?
We have or what's do we have any ideas
for that?
And.
Um,
I think it would be cool to have like a...
Do you know the Roman names?
Like, uh, Cassius, um...
Okay.
Mhm.
Bologna.
Cassius, Caesar, Bellona, Ares,
do you want gods or something like that,
Yeah, yeah, oh.
or gods and kind of ancient Roman names,
that style?
No, I think it would be,
I think it would be pretty cool to have
just like, like names like that,
but then you could also have like Greek
names as to as well.
Mhm.
Um...
And kind of depending on where they're
from,
they'll kind of have like different names
where they come from, if that makes sense.
Yeah,
and do other characters in the world,
so characters you don't play, the NPCs,
do they have similar style names or do
they have a different style names?
Um...
Yeah,
they might have like different names.
I feel like it's more nobility,
they'll have more eccentric and more...
like stronger names and like the average
maybe town you might just have like a
stem from that.
Name from them.
So, like,
if they're for if they are beside this
like Roman Empire as such.
And they're far out from that town,
from that city.
They'll have a stem of them sort of names,
but not as strong.
That makes sense.
Okay, so it's kind of like, it's like,
yeah,
you want them to fit a theme for the area.
So technically then the characters in
Yeah.
this,
they're not having names that are like
unique, if you know what I mean,
they're just kind of trying to fit in the
area. And so then like even NPCs,
they're like,
Mhm.
so everyone in this world has similar
names. So the names that they have,
Is that what, like,
are they going to be called their
original name or are they going to be
called the name that was like given to
them by their parents or whatever way,
for example?
I think you should be able to do both.
Like, you have nearly like a nickname.
But do you have your real name?
when you're introducing yourself.
Both.
Be like, oh, my name is Caesar,
but everyone calls me a kid.
Okay.
Right, I get you there now. So yeah,
you want nicknames or titles,
But.
Yeah.
like what you'll be renowned for.
Yeah.
Like if you're like a party of you hunt
goblins,
like you might have the title Goblin
Hunter Caesar.
Okay, cool. Oh yeah,
and sometimes it might be important their
name, but people are like, oh,
that's the Golden Killer,
Yeah.
that's the Golden Hunter. Yep.
So you can get Renown through the name as
Yeah.
well. Nice, nice. Okay.
So you know when we kind of discussed
before, like what,
like how is the world start and how it
might kind of play out.
Do you remember what I was talking to you
about or do you have any ideas yourself
Mhm.
Yeah.
that you want to walk through?
I remember you talked about how like
people were falling from the sky and
landing onto the floor.
You had the original 16 characters and
Mhm.
they were at like the high veil or pretty
much godhood and they've been thrown back
Done.
Yeah.
That was essentially what it was, was it?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's pretty much what it was.
So I was saying like we set the scene.
So at the very start,
it'll be like you have all the characters.
So the 16 characters are all up in this
kind of heavenly place or this kind of
place where they have like godhood and
there'll be some sort of disaster up
there and everyone,
all 16 of them will be sent down to Earth.
And then, when they're sent down to Earth.
Mm.
Yeah.
The.
should be maybe set in stone so you don't
get it so the characters get the name who
Mhm.
they're playing like so and we could get
that one to fit maybe the theme of like
Yeah.
god-style names.
Okay, yeah, no, that's a good idea.
I like that.
Awesome.
And when they crash on the Earth,
they lose their memories.
So all 16 lose their memories.
And they go,
they get sent to different places on the
Earth.
Yeah.
So we can kind of like randomise like
where they'd crash land.
So we're going to have to think of a
thing where like they'll crash land and
they look
the exact same as they used to do.
So from the start,
they still look like the,
how they did in God form,
but they don't really stand out as much.
You know,
they kind of look like a regular,
a regular person on this earth.
Yep.
And then they,
Okay, so you have that.
Then each one land,
like some people land in castles,
some people land out in the forest,
some people land at, you know, cities,
towns, worlds.
But regardless of where they land,
some people land in kind of, let's say,
bad areas, good areas,
all that sort of stuff. And
Basically, what happens is,
is that you're choosing a character at
the start,
and let's say you choose the first
character. Let's just say you said...
Cassius. So you choose Cassius.
So Cassius now is no longer an NPC and
Yeah.
Cassius is your character.
So in the world where you're playing as
Yeah.
Cassius.
that personality type is removed,
all his NPC behaviors,
and then every other one of the 15 has
their same.
Behaviors.
Okay.
of personality types.
Hey, I have one thing as well. When,
let's say for example,
you choose Katsius and you land at this
place,
what's your objective or is it kind of...
Yeah.
Curran.
Like when you have an initial goal,
like it might come up like on a little
screen and be like, climb the tower.
That's your objective or.
Yeah.
You know what? That's a good point,
and I think that instead of maybe getting
rid of kind of like each of the 16
characters should have like a set of
quests or missions in the stories that
kind of lead them to eventually climb in
the tower.
Yeah.
and getting through it because whatever
way the world works out,
like you could eventually get those
details or someone will get those details
to figure out like, oh no,
you have to send the tower to try to get
back into this godhood place.
Hey.
But you don't know what you're fighting
for.
Yeah, that's good.
And what I was thinking from it as well,
let's say you're playing Cassius. You now,
Yeah.
you play Cassius,
you go through the storyline of whatever
happens in his life and you climb to the
top of the tower.
So when you go past the top of the tower
and you beat it,
and you're fighting against the other
Earth kings.
So it's just basically found out that
like, you know,
these towers were actually a proving
ground for seeing if you could defend
Earth from the other multiverse.
Mhm.
And then the character in each of the
other 15 towers is a max level version of
the NPCs.
So even if that NPC died in your world or,
you know, didn't happen, like whatever,
like each one of them has to be the max
level of what that character could have
been.
Mhm.
And that's how everyone's going to fight.
I don't know if some people will have
parties or some people won't have parties,
because, you know,
some people will just not maybe not work
too good in a party. Some people might.
Some people might even team up with
original people that came from that
heaven.
Yeah.
What do you think?
So like you can find them in world and
you can team up with them. Yeah,
but you don't have to team up with them.
Yeah, no, that's good.
Mhm.
Okay, cool.
I think it'd be good,
like they kind of have their own lives
and they kind of just do whatever and
they land wherever and they end up.
doing whatever they want and eventually
you might cross paths with them.
Ohh.
Do you think that the characters will
know who they are or will they get a
feeling that like,
I should know who this person is or
Hmm.
should it be straight up like,
or straight up like, oh,
I know this person?
Yeah.
This is so and so.
I see, I think it should be clear to the..
.
To the player that, yeah,
you would know each other.
But I wonder...
Mhm.
Because I would.
It could be something,
it could be something that like all 16 of
the characters have something that all of
them have.
So maybe like a tattoo or like they have.
their eyes might glow or they might have
like something that can recognise the
other one.
You're like, hold on,
how the hell does that guy have that
Yeah.
tattoo in the same place?
He has some way of recognising each other.
Yeah, I like that. I like that. Yeah,
Same as me.
there's got to be some way that they
could potentially know each other.
And then I guess the main character,
which is you,
you'll have already played the intro.
So you'll have fallen to us.
Mhm.
You'll probably recognise these guys.
Mhm.
As you're going,
as you're kind of going around, I guess,
in a way, maybe your memories are intact.
Yeah.
Or at least whatever you've actually seen,
because...
Yeah,
that would be very interesting there.
Yeah, what things you've seen that side.
Okay.
Yeah.
Very interesting now.
Could be, could be,
could be something interesting there.
Hey,
is there any other questions we can go
through?
Yeah,
so I think we've gone through a lot of
the character stuff.
Yeah,
so maybe just for the characters as well,
like, you know,
they should be as kind of available to
get different classes and stuff and we
kind of want to set them up so they
follow a lot of kind of their personality
types plus different types.
We want big variety,
like you kind of want 16 different
characters that have to have 16 different
ways of fighting.
if you know what I mean.
Yeah.
Yeah, okay. So yeah,
so what kind of man or anime or anything?
Is there any kind of like inspiration
characters you think would be good to put
down as possible?
This is just going to be able to fill out
the dialogue and fill out what these type
of people are.
Um...
For example,
you have Thorfinn from Vinland Saga.
He's A dual-wielding,
kind of like bandit in a way.
And he has just so much hate.
Towards a certain person,
and he wants to get stronger to surpass
them and eventually kill them,
so he's driven by hatred.
Yeah.
You have.
Sun Jin Woo from Solo Leveling,
and he is pretty much powered by...
Getting stronger,
like he just wants to get stronger in
every way.
Um...
Mhm.
You have Monkey D.
Luffy from One Piece and he just wants to
be free.
So.
Yeah.
They're quite good characters.
Yeah.
Okay, yeah,
so that was kind of the main character as
well. And then I think, like, you know,
like you have pain from the Naruto series,
you know, because he's...
Got a powerful, um, oh, okay.
Sorry, so someone messaged me here now,
one second.
No butter.
Yeah.
Okay, perfect.
Mhm.
So, because that sort of there,
grand stuff, yes,
so you've all the kind of different
characters. I know, yeah,
there's some amazing characters all over
the different manga, anime, and mana. So,
but like, yeah,
it's a lot of interesting characters
there.
I guess it's definitely to take
inspiration there and how we're going to
fit in people into the world,
because I think that the story
will start shaping itself after we've got
all these characters. But to be honest,
I'm not too worried about what someone's
backstory is or what their ambitions are.
That's part of the game,
you know what I mean?
And could be some fun.
Yeah, definitely.
So, yeah,
and we can always come back to that after,
see if we need to fix stuff. So,
pools and casting.
Okay, yeah, so I...
Maybe.
What?
I was going to say maybe go up to the top
so that you can see which questions.
Are there available,
or is there is there more here?
Yeah.
Yeah, we can do that.
So.
So,
which ones do we kind of want to go over?
I think that, yeah, what's this?
Elekes.
I think these ones,
we can leave them just for now.
Yeah.
Things where mechanics and fiction scrape.
Um...
Let's have a little look at this VIINVI,
so pools and casting.
And then we can come back to mechanics
then straight after, yeah.
Yeah.
And stuff.
Rules and casting, right?
So this is about history, background,
relationship.
background, grant, books, gifts,
what tags can two people from? So right,
okay,
so we've actually covered a lot of the
background already.
but it's,
they're going to be all coming from the
same place in this overworld type area
and they both all crash land. How much,
how long of a background do we want to
include in the story for characters?
Oleg.
Um...
I feel like you'll learn more and it will
get bigger as time goes on.
Okay, yeah,
so we want to have a background then.
Um, you might find out more.
You'll have,
you'll have like a steady one,
Krzysztof.
like a short enough one.
Yeah,
and then it just starts going perfect,
And you'll start up more.
yeah, so yeah, you can you can add on,
so background can keep growing.
Okay, cool.
And 2 characters can share a similar
background because, like,
it just depends on if those parts get
revealed,
like maybe the uniqueness of them can be
revealed after, but for the most part,
you know,
everyone's going to be similar in
different ways.
Mhm.
Okay, so yeah,
we've covered a lot of this stuff. Yeah,
so should there be any guilds or creeds
or something like that?
Definitely, 100%.
Yeah, different groups.
I think such some characters should
obviously be involved in them as well.
Like there should be, yes,
Yes, I agree.
there should be characters that are
involved in every aspect, like religion,
guilds, you know, royalty, towns, cities,
wildlife.
you know, adventurers, you know, hunting,
like all the different roles of bandits,
like there should always be a character
somehow involved with that particular
group.
Mhm.
and then some are just nomads as well.
But there's, yes,
it's a very easy way for giving that
person more history.
If they stay aligned with that faction,
that's up to the base.
There can always be ways of doing this,
just to give all the NPCs.
That part, yeah.
So do the oncast pieces really become
rumors? Yeah, that's, yeah,
we can keep those rumours and stuff given
for other characters.
Does the player ever see a character's
full history? So what would we show?
I feel like the more you find out,
the more you get to reveal about the
character's history.
Yep.
Yeah,
and there's different stuff that can be
revealed.
as you kind of progress and there's
certain milestones once you unlock them
or once you talk to certain people,
it'll feed into your own background that
you can read.
Is the 16 characters originally from this
world?
So, that's a good question. Like,
then I don't think that there is any from
Like.
this world.
They would have been in a world above.
Yeah.
and they crashed down there and they've,
because there's some sort of...
disaster that happens and basically when
they got crashed down to Earth,
that's when the actual multiverse was
split and so the 16 characters.
actually are the ones that were sent to
one character per one of the universes.
So the 15 guys that you'll see after you
choose your character,
Yeah, I got you.
they're actually just copies of the
original.
Yes, yeah.
So then technically that means like,
you know, there'll always be a copy.
So you'll actually deal with the original
guys in each one of their worlds when you
go to eventually have that tournament at
the top.
The.
Yep.
And then you'll get to find out who was
the,
what was the reason that that happened,
who created it,
and what's the next kind of,
what's the stages for deciding who's
going to become the Earth King or why,
why or how someone must survive or
someone must be like, you know,
last alive or maybe the group up together.
Yep.
They fight a different opponent,
who knows,
but every single person there will have
completed the tower. So,
and then it's like time stops until
everyone completes the tower.
Okay.
So that's why they all completed
technically the same time,
so no one's waiting.
I have one question.
Is there multiple towers or is there one
Yes.
tower?
Yeah, that's what I've been wondering.
And what do you think, Ian?
I think if you wanted to do like one
massive tower in the middle that has,
let's say, 100 floors,
but then scattered all around the world
has like the gates and they'd be like
different dungeons and
Mhm.
Uh,
explorable places that you find mobs and
defeat bosses, and...
Yeah.
Elekes that.
Oh yeah, I was thinking as well,
is that so every time you climb a floor
in the tower,
it kicks you out of the tower and you
come back into the real world.
Mhm.
And so when that happens,
the story progresses or the world's story
progresses.
And for you to get into the next floor of
the tower,
sometimes you might have to have a
certain item or you might must have some
sort of
other thing completed to be able to
progress, if you know what I mean.
Yeah, yeah.
And that's how gates can get involved.
That's how different things,
maybe it's every five levels you need to
have some other way of getting access to
the next batch of stores.
And that's when the story is involved.
Yeah.
You must, yeah, yeah, yeah,
that's good incentivization to clear the
gates, as well as climbing the tower.
Yeah. And so if you like, for example,
if you don't clear the gates or you don't
interact with the world at all by the
main quest,
then you've no control over what's going
to happen after you clear the next few
floors of the tower.
Like presumably the world always gets
tougher if you don't clear it because
Okay.
Hi.
like, you know,
you're leaving XP at the side and all
these potential chances to fully level up.
Um, I also,
is there such thing as a timer?
Do I have to complete?
Events in a certain amount of time,
and if I don't, what happens if I fail?
Yeah, it's another good question as well,
like, because I can make it difficult to..
.
to progress.
I think it's definitely an element we
should consider. But for the most part,
I think we should try to test what
happens when we're playing first to see
what's even interesting.
Instead of getting like kind of pushed
towards certain things.
Yeah, yeah.
I think that the time the world should
only really change after you complete,
let's say, five floors of the tower.
Yeah.
So after like the,
you complete the 5th floor,
then the world changes, 10th floor,
then the world updates, that sort of way.
So yeah,
and then you can update all the different
Yeah, good idea.
storylines if you want.
But we need to have a way of like
Yeah.
tracking what quest you can do,
my characters,
but I'm just thinking what actually
happens if your character dies?
If your character dies,
I think it would be quite cool to see,
like...
The world.
Just like,
almost like a cinematic nearly of the
world that you're in,
just slowly just get destroyed.
You see it like an overtop view.
Okay.
Uh,
because you're supposed to save it if you
don't, if you die.
Mhm.
And save it,
or it could be the case of you can.
But I've actually had a question,
just I was even going to,
I was just going to build on what you're
saying Ian,
but you know the way that there's 16
different.
A universes.
Mhm.
So how about if your world,
so if you die in your world and that
world gets destroyed and it plays the
animation,
should you then have a choice of becoming
the character in the 15 remaining ones?
Okay, yeah, so like...
In the same world or the like an
alternate world?
That's what I'm wondering. I'm wondering,
does it just throw you into the alternate
world?
Because technically they're the only
player characters.
Because if you get to swap to them,
I think you should be at the same level
of the tower, for example, as well.
Like you should have all the same
progression that you had in your world.
But the...
Yeah, you can just tell stuff's different.
And then, like,
let's say if you were to reach the end of
the game,
so instead of fighting 7 and 16 people to
fight each other,
you only fight among who's left.
Yeah, cool.
They've survived their world and stuff.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
But yeah, but I wonder...
Could be like 5 minutes.
Yeah, I wonder what would change, though,
when you're choosing a different,
so after your first character dies,
it sends you into the other one.
Like what would actually be changed?
Hey, it.
It's, yeah, it's kind of the case, like,
are you choosing...
Let's say your character dies and you go
to the next guy.
Are they going,
you're saying they're going to be the
exact same sort of level?
I think that they should, yeah,
they should be the same level or the same
Bought.
kind of level of progression through the
world.
So if you've cleared 5 floors of the
tower.
You should also have cleared 5 floors
that are in this world, shouldn't you?
It's, in my opinion, I think that...
This game?
Isn't easy, like...
Okay.
I don't think that when your character
dies, you can just keep your progression.
I think that's the work that you put in
with that character.
Or you go into the other world with more
knowledge of how to get stronger and you
start off at level 1 again. It's like,
okay,
Yeah.
what can I do right now with this
character?
I completely agree you and I agree as
well. Yeah.
So that's the idea we're going to go for.
We're going to follow your idea.
And so each,
since you have got a history or
experience what happened in one of the
worlds,
like this world could potentially play
out very similar.
So if you were looking for where a
certain character crash landed or for
where a certain item is,
then you could go to that place.
Yes.
Yeah.
So yeah,
and then that's the kind of the idea is,
is that right?
So once your character died,
then you've actually absorbed your
knowledge into the new character.
Yeah.
So he can feel like, oh, I've got...
I've got the Cassius, his ghost guides me.
Yeah.
Well, they like you've chosen, yeah,
that's very cool, yeah.
Mhm.
Yeah, I like that. That'd be very fun.
Like, yes, you start off again,
but this time you get to play that
character and then the world that was
destroyed is destroyed.
They can never come back.
So you essentially got 16 chances to beat
the game or beat the original storyline
Yeah, that's good.
or then you'll have to...
You won't have anyone to fight.
That's cool.
Yeah, that's cool.
And I think that, based on how many,
how many or what characters actually
survive.
The.
To the final,
it can make some really interesting,
different kind of end game. I mean,
who's going to fight,
Yeah.
what's going to fight this sort of way?
Yep, I agree.
So, and should...
Basically, you see the way,
let's say you make it,
you beat the whole game with that
character and one of the,
like two of the worlds have already
perished. Those,
the ghosts go to every other guy.
Or do they just go to one?
And.
Or does a fragment?
So let's say if one character dies,
then he splits off into 15 parts,
and so he gives a part to each one.
I actually don't, I actually don't know.
Mhm.
The only thing I can think on could be
almost like a force ghost. Oh like.
When let's say you go to a campfire,
then you can maybe interact.
Through meditation with the previous
character.
Yeah.
Kind of like or like all for one or one
for all.
Yeah.
when Izuka Midoriya can interact with all
those different characters,
I like that.
like the first owner, the second owner,
third owner, all the way up to himself.
Mhm.
Yeah, I, you and I like that,
and so what separates then, like,
you as a player with...
the other potential players. It's like,
is there,
I guess the player decides what order he
organises the one for all,
but that's kind of what it's like.
So you get bonuses to your second
character after your first character dies.
Um...
I suppose maybe like.
I think I just got an idea of like...
You have your 16 characters,
you choose your one,
you go and you go to a campfire and you
meditate and you can see the four scopes
of all the other characters,
but you can't interact with them until
they've died.
And when you, when they've died,
they make themselves maybe physical in a
Yes.
way, but not, they're still...
Yeah.
completely a ghost, if that makes sense.
And you can talk to them, interact,
ask questions like how did they fail?
Maybe like...
What they did really good,
and maybe some like...
We could give you some quests.
It'd be like,
I actually found this in this location.
And you can maybe get some quests from
Oh, very gorgeous.
them, maybe, I don't know.
So it should be the,
when you're playing the game,
you're generating your quest log and your
journal and everything you've done.
So that if that character dies,
that journal gets saved.
And then that can be like some of the
bits that he reveals to the next person.
If you're asking them around the campfire,
just talking to force ghosts and then
that'll help them kind of say,
because you're not going to remember
Yeah, yeah.
everything you've done.
Mhm.
with the characters.
So yeah, that's very cool, Ian.
I love that.
Anything else kind of on that,
or will we take a look at some other
stuff?
Um...
I suppose it would be,
since you have all the different
personalities for the characters,
some characters just will not give you
information,
some characters might give you all of it,
some might withhold information,
and you probably might have to like...
Gain up like a synergy in a way, so...
Mhm.
The more you talk to them or the more you
kind of help them do quests or like
interact with them,
the more likely they'll tell you more
stuff and share more information.
Do you know what? Yeah,
you know what I was thinking, you know,
is what if every character had a weapon
that was built just for them and then...
That's what you're supposed to like,
get from your own world.
So before the world gets destroyed,
it creates your,
the main character becomes a ghost and
then his custom weapon actually gets sent
over into the next world of crash land
somewhere.
And if you can find that weapon,
then you can unlock.
Basically,
whatever you need to off the previous
character.
Yeah, yeah,
so you give them their initial weapon and
that's when you can interact with them.
Is that what you're kind of saying?
Yes, you can interact with them before,
but I think that...
Once you get that weapon or that that
piece of them.
Yeah,
maybe that's where you can interact with
them and you get everything off them.
Will it be somewhere in your world? Yeah,
I think so.
I think that if you find that weapon,
because it becomes like rumours and stuff
set up,
so eventually you would be able to find
it.
Mm.
And then this comes down to where you
want, maybe it could even be a reward for.
..
Climbing the tower, would that be right,
or should it be somewhere in the world?
No,
I think it would be cool if it crash
lands onto the world and I think that
other people might take that weapon and
you're like, ****,
I'm actually going to have to get this
weapon often. And yeah,
it could land anywhere.
Yeah.
Yeah, command anywhere. And it's like a,
it's like a,
what we say like a god tier weapon or
something like that.
Yeah, it's a god-tier weapon,
but it's not your proficiency,
so you can't use it unless maybe you
train up or something.
Yeah.
Yeah, so it'd be like, yeah,
so getting that back could be difficult,
but it would definitely be worth it.
Yeah.
The.
Nice, nice, nice, nice. And potentially,
I guess the first time,
maybe you make it easy to find where the
weapon is, or maybe it's just random.
Yeah, cool.
Just so when you want, yeah,
that's really cool. Really, really cool.
Okay,
let's have a look at some of that stuff.
K.
Let's cheque a look at mechanics and
carried over.
Yeah.
A.
Okay, never mind.
Is this?
Maybe go to boundaries, so this is like,
it's not in it.
Yeah.
Sean all the boundaries, yeah, perfect.
It's like never true.
Yeah, okay.
Name one thing that must never be true.
Name one thing you want so badly.
What tone would make you stop working on
this?
Six, what would you drop?
What are you afraid this game will turn
into?
Okay, yeah, let's say, right,
so now we're going to answer what we
don't want the game to be like.
So this is just basically, yeah,
like what kind of, I guess.
What kind of tone and stuff?
What do you think in your end?
Um...
I don't want this game to be repetitive.
Okay.
And.
I think, as more time goes on...
The issue gets darker in a way.
Yeah.
Um...
Like the tone I would give this game is a
dark fantasy, if that makes sense.
Yeah, I think the same way,
because that's how the world's gearing up
and how I think it's actually going to
play out.
Mm.
Things that I don't want,
it's kind of a hard way,
kind of a hard question.
Yeah,
well you don't want it to be in like a
*******.
boring game either, you know,
it's just like, it's all laughs and stuff.
Mhm.
It's going to be dark fantasy.
You don't want it to be like that the
fights just turn into the exact same set
of moves every time and that you're just
kind of grinding through.
So you want a little bit of dialogue,
but you don't want to be held up by
dialogue either.
And I think that the fights is something
that we really need to get done right.
Yeah.
Because like,
we've got loads of abilities at the
minute, but remember we said for like,
like it could be similar to pokémon where
you had like 4 abilities you could have
active at one time.
Maybe you've got passives as well that
you don't have to activate.
Yeah.
But like there should be some ways of
enabling.
Like, enable it to be fun, like, because..
.
Yeah,
you don't want it to be just kind of
grinding and boring and repetitive.
Mhm.
So,
I guess what I'm afraid the game will
turn into is that...
Like going up the 100 floors is just not.
Fun, like maybe 100 floors is too much.
Maybe it's not enough.
Maybe, you know,
maybe there should be a smaller amount of
floors in the tower.
Maybe there's...
There should be some like it should be
set up that like it's an achievable goal.
and you kind of, you know,
that you want to climb the tower.
So like there's going to be information
or maybe flashbacks or other stuff.
Mhm.
You can check.
But, oh, I actually have an idea.
So this would be something that would be
good,
is that when you pass the 5th floor in
the tower.
you get like an image that like, oh,
all 16 people are alive.
And then everywhere you go up,
you get all 16 people are alive.
But then when you die off your first
character, you die on the 10th floor.
So when you swap to the next character,
it says all 16 people are alive.
Then when you get to the 10th floor,
it says, oh,
Only 15 of us are alive,
so that tracks with, like,
Oh.
while you're stepping through,
it's going to show you who's alive, like,
Yeah, yeah.
because you won't be able to play them in
parallel,
but I think that the new character
shouldn't.
Yeah.
Find out anything until...
the other characters actually died and
that's the same way of that there
shouldn't be a weapon.
In your next character's world,
until they've at least progressed past
the previous world.
That's great. Yeah, that's perfect.
Yeah.
I was going back on your point about the
fights.
Yeah.
I have a really good idea of how the
fights would work instead of like
turn-based.
Mhm.
I think that we should take a lot of
inspiration from this game called Dungeon
Settlers.
It has point and click,
point and click to go where you want to
Okay.
go, but it's on this tile sheet.
And...
Yeah.
Your characters automatically use their
attacks,
and you have QWER would be your abilities
you want to use,
or you can use auto abilities.
See, if you scroll,
if you scroll down there a little bit.
Yes.
Oh yeah, yeah, I like that idea.
And.
And, like,
you can pause the game whenever you want,
or you can speed up the game whenever you
need, as well.
Yeah.
It kind of has like building your houses
and stuff with it too,
but that's not really, we don't need that.
Yeah, maybe.
And then it...
They keep going.
It would kind of like.
It would kind of like speed up that, like,
that tile system if you want to go faster.
Yeah.
and get away from the XCOM sort of fight
and style, we can do it that way,
Yes.
which would be a good idea.
But if we want to keep the XCOM sort of
style turn-based strategy,
we can do that too.
We can find other ways of making it
better.
Yeah, no, I really like, yeah,
the dungeon settlers gameplay type,
because it'll definitely be very fun for
kind of getting through his dark fantasy
as well. Yeah,
we'll do an in-depth research on that.
So I'm just making a note here as well in
the voice note that we need a big,
big research,
deep dive using AI into the combat.
of dungeon settlers and exactly what
they're trying to achieve in it.
That's cool.
Yeah, I agree with that.
Anything else you're kind of wondering,
The.
like what about animations and stuff like
that when people are using abilities?
Another game I am thinking of is Kingdom
Hearts, no sorry, Kingdom Hearts,
Fire Emblem, Three Houses.
When the characters,
it's kind of like that grid sheet XCOM
style, but when they use their attacks,
they have a sort of animation of them
using their abilities.
Is that when they just use strong
abilities or is that just when they use?
Oh,
anything like if they're shooting a bow,
it'll be like they're loading up the
arrow and they shoot it,
and then they make their attack.
Ohh, yes.
I get you there, yes,
you get to actually see them.
They are sending off their attack at each
one. Yeah.
Yeah.
So they're actually animated that they
are fighting,
but it's going to be in the dungeon
settlers type fight style.
So the animations are actually clean for
what they're doing.
Okay, yeah, that could be good,
really good animations.
Fire Emblem Three House animation style
for combat,
then Dungeon Settlers actual combat
mechanics and click,
click and play style and for speeding up
and slowing down. Yeah, that's cool.
Okay, very interesting.
What else are you kind of thinking, Lynn?
Um...
If we're going the XCOM sort of route
with the tiles.
Then we have to put in, or or.
No,
I think I think it's going the way you
know you've said already for dungeon
settlers and stuff.
Okay, cool, cool, yeah.
I think it's I think it's just way better,
yeah.
Okay, cool, that's...
Way better ideas for moving around in the
car. Yeah, a lot more fun.
That's handy.
There's also a game called Kenshi K.E.N.S.
H.I. and.
Mhm.
Pretty much the way that you level up in
this game is by repetition.
So if you have a level 1 character,
they'll have level 1 every,
look at the Kenti ability tree or level
in.
Where is it?
CW.
So, if you can kind of see, there's...
Yeah, if you can kind of see,
it will have like...
Cortana's at level fifty-seven,
so that's through repetition of using the
Cortanas that it's gotten better at.
Okay, yeah, so proficiency on each skill,
fight types, yeah.
Yeah, and with sabers,
he's actually level 3,
Yes.
so he's not that good with them.
Yeah.
Um...
So,
that's like a good way of maybe getting
better with...
A nicer way of getting better with a
weapon that you get a proficiency with it
Mhm.
in comparison to just having the level 50
Katana and you can just...
Use that weapon.
Yeah, yeah, I agree with you then.
It could be like an add-on like that,
them to compare with each other
proficiency and actually whatever the
weapon is.
Yeah, I agree with you on that.
That's cool.
Um...
Be in that way.
A.
I mean,
a really good one if you go on dark
fantasy is like Souls, like Dark Souls,
Elden Ring, they kind of have like...
As more levels are getting put in,
it needs more XP to be put into any of
the other levels, if that makes sense.
Yeah, and what about the, do you know,
in surviving the dungeon as a barbarian,
Yeah.
like the first time you defeat?
Any type of character?
then you unlock XP for that.
You unlock like you're whatever, one XP,
Boop.
but then no matter how many you fight of
that character,
you don't get any XP but you can get
proficiency.
Yeah, I like that too. That's a good one.
Yeah,
so professions that you can get through
practice, but experience points,
it needs to be a unique character.
So if you're involved in a fight where
that character dies,
then you get the experience point.
I think that'll be a good way of
controlling the XP game,
so you can't just get XP from...
You know, uh...
Spamming,
killing goblin raids or something.
Yeah, I think.
And you get passwords levels.
And I think it'll make it handy as well.
Like that's why you'd want to go into to
There is.
do dungeons and stuff and you'd want to
fight new areas because then they'll
Yep.
introduce new opponents that you can
fight and you can level up. Yeah,
Yeah.
that's really cool.
And what's actually I suppose now that we
mentioned that what's the what is in a
dungeon gate? Is it just a dungeon?
And.
And A dungeon gates,
I think that it can range from anything.
Have you read Tower of God or...?
Add a little bit of a jam.
How, when they go into the tower level,
it's like...
Its size of the map can be any size,
but it can be a completely different
Yeah.
world, basically,
like a like a ice ice biome,
and it's all ice elves, and...
Yeah.
You might go into one and it's like...
It's a desert and you have to fight like
scorpion monsters and maybe like, gotcha,
what's that name? Pick me up,
infinite gotcha. Oh,
it's like you go into a gate and it's
like...
pretty much like a period of time and you
have to complete an objective.
Yeah,
so should it always be an objective you
have to complete when you go into a case?
I think if you go into a gate,
you can't leave until you beat it.
Okay,
and then what's the difference between
that and the tower?
So you go into a floor in the tower.
Um...
A gate.
A tower will be...
Um.
I don't know, what's your idea on that?
Yeah, it's a good one, isn't it?
Because the tower,
I guess the tower has to be some sort of
test of strength or some test of
improvement or has to provide a challenge
scaled.
to make sure like you're worthy of going
to the next floor.
So you still have to do objectives,
but it's more trying to test the player.
and then a gate.
can have like a different set of
objectives and it's not trying to test
the player, it's trying to test the world,
if you know what I mean.
Yeah.
Like,
it's something that's happening to the
world,
so you have to think of some way to stop
the gates,
but then the tower is like an actual,
like,
like it's an honourable kind of way of
climbing, 'cause other...
NPCs in the game are also trying to climb
the tower.
AI.
And they're doing it their own way,
but it's like, yeah,
you're known for like...
you know, you can take more experience.
I guess it's like Adventurers Guild.
They're more focused on,
they're more focused on the...
I was just thinking that.
Gates and stuff and royalty folks on
gates,
but then strong individuals always want
to climb.
the tower, whereas the gates might,
you might have a whole army, for example,
that are looking to take out a gate and
you can all enter together,
Yes.
but then a tower is just restricted to
your party when you're going in.
Yeah, good idea. That's good. I like that.
Nice, yeah,
and then the objectives are whatever,
whatever we think would be more suitable
to both.
That's good, that's good. I like that.
Yeah, yeah, nice, nice.
And of the gates have different ranks as
well, so.
They're like a little bit random chance,
but the...
Yeah, I guess like the,
it's definitely say difficulty,
but for example, an S-class case,
that's like a national level threat.
And that means that like, you know,
you'd expect that there's a lot of people.
Preparing to enter it together.
Mm.
Maybe a few kingdoms, an army,
something like that.
All the strongest guys,
they wait until they have enough strong
Yeah.
guys to get in.
And in that sort of way,
and I guess the Adventures Guild as well
is trying to help manage that too.
Let's have a look at that. It's cool. Oh,
very cool.
Yeah.
And anything else popping out at you
there, Ian?
Um...
I would like a system in the game where...
If you have a party,
you could send some of your party members
to do things for you, if it's...
Collect herbs so that you can make
medicine,
or if it's meat with a certain individual,
or carry out a task,
Yeah.
or simply like join a gate raid,
but you be off doing your own thing,
and then they'll tell you how.
Yeah.
went or they got on and they might die as
well.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, that's very interesting.
Yeah,
so we have different ways that you can
command whoever you're allied with.
If they're in your party,
is your party then like capped to a
certain size or is it something that,
you know,
you could be in charge of a guild or is
that?
Um...
You just have people your lunch and so on.
I think.
I think initially your party is
definitely like capped at, let's say, 4.
Okay.
Yeah.
And you might be able to,
I think like 6 in your parties is like a
good number.
You can get like a lot of different
Yeah.
Call.
versatility on that.
Okay. Yeah.
I think that should be kind of enough.
Yeah.
Yeah, okay. I agree with that. Yeah,
we will have some way of sending them off
to do something.
Nice,
and they travel across the world in real
time, do they?
Yeah, like when you're traveling,
they're travelling too, and...
So maybe, you know,
the way like you're getting objectives
that are popping up in the game,
like quests and stuff like that there,
and you're hearing rumors,
like it's all getting out of your like
potential quest or job log.
And maybe you could just be clicking on
Mhm.
one day, you're like, all right,
send these three over here,
send these two over here.
And that sort of way.
Mhm.
And so what happens if one of your...
Party characters that you sent over to
complete a job?
What if they get a first kill on a new
enemy?
Does that unlock it for the whole party?
No.
It doesn't.
No, no, no,
I think I think it should be individual.
Okay.
Okay, so what happens if like,
for example,
if you have a healer and they're not
getting the last hit on anything,
or do you just have to be involved in the
actual...
I think you can get like an assist in a
way, like if you're involved, you'll get,
The father.
you'll get, I get what you mean.
Maybe it's like the case of if it's a
healer.
And.
No.
Uh, you're healing a character,
you're assisting them and they've maybe
killed 5 of that character,
that's when you get your full XP.
And what happens then if it's like a,
if it's a one-time boss?
Of.
It's A one-time boss.
I think boss fights should be different.
I think boss fights,
everyone will get the XP. Or like...
Yeah.
Normal grunts and different foot soldiers,
it'll be like assist with 10 and you'll
get the full XP,
but the character who gets the last hit
will get the full XP.
Yeah, yeah, I get you. OK, yeah, so...
If.
if you're within proximity.
of an enemy that looks like it's a big
enough proximity,
like if you're kind of involved in the
fight or however it works out,
and you don't get the final hit,
you get an assist. And then after...
Five times of being in a sister,
you get the XP point for that particular
enemy.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and then you've got a reason to try to
find farm certain enemies and try to find
them all over.
Yeah, and that's interesting. Yeah,
and whoever gets the last,
it does get the XP. Nice.
That's cool.
Mm.
I suppose another thing is, in three days,
your monthly Pixel Lab AI will...
Oh.
Mhm.
Be reset to 0 credits used.
So we do have like 15% left on that.
Okay.
Yeah,
so we need to get a full list of what
potential things we need,
like we need to make use of pixel AI.
So we need to have an organised list of
what we need to animate.
Mhm.
In conjunction with the design, yeah.
So I'll make a full that we need to make
a,
so I'm making a big note now in this
voice note that we need to have a full
list of what potentially needs to be
designed to fit the new world and to fit
what's designed so far in terms of maps,
characters, animations.
enemies, abilities,
like anything related to the game.
And we're going to generate them using
Pixel Lab.
And so we can use Pixel Lab and A Sprite.
So let us know how these characters
should be designed and what you expect
them to be able to do, or abilities,
movements, etc.
Behave, yeah, okay, that's good.
That's great.
It's good.
Cool, cool. Anything else there?
Um...
I don't know.
The question there, are there gods?
Do they act?
Does anyone claim to have seen one?
What do you think about that?
So I think that the 16 characters that
crashed down to Earth could be considered
either gods or demigods.
And whenever they get to the end game and
they're now up against the other
Versions.
Of the of them, like the other.
people who are originally were at the
start.
Yeah.
They should have to.
fight or complete the quest or do
something that's actually taken on the
real God.
So are the real God or the real like
anti-God?
Like the super bad guy.
I think we should make them maybe
demigods as best, do you think?
The.
Yeah, demigod sounds good.
Yeah,
the characters are demigods and actually
there is actually gods as well.
But that's after you've climbed up the
tower and you've gotten to the part where
you get pulled into the universe level
and then Earth Kings.
Everyone knows that one world is going to
be left stand at the end.
Yep.
And that's how people are going to figure
it out.
So there's a force that can actually
obviously do that.
So you need to figure out how you're
going to stop that.
Another thing.
We need to figure out, um...
Is.
I suppose, like,
what size are we making the characters?
I know that's another thing that will be
done with the notes from Excel Lab.
What?
Like 16 bit is like Dungeon Settlers,
32 bit is a little bit more and then 64
Mhm.
is what we were initially doing.
Okay.
Yeah, I don't,
there might not be a need for... Yeah,
we do want to make it manageable.
So we start with 64.
Do.
see any reason to go down to a lower
quality unit or...
I think, um...
Hmm, like maybe not, but like...
32.
If you want to look at the comparison
between the lot, look up 8 bits, 16 bits,
32 bits, 64 bits.
Differences.
Mhm.
Let me look at the images for a second
image that.
Yeah.
Like that.
Kind of is like a big difference,
like the 64 bit is pretty much 3D.
Yeah,
it could be a little bit hard for us to...
I think 64 bits.
You see, it's not exactly sixty-four bit,
it's more of like the size.
Mhm.
Sixty-four by sixty-four, the pixel art.
If that there would be thirty-two.
Or maybe 16.
Yeah.
Yeah, you're right.
It is something to consider.
Mm.
Yeah,
well what about are you happy with the
characters that we've seen so far?
Yeah, like, they're quite cool, like,
they're...
Speaking.
There, they are very good, like,
and we can continue almost sixty-four.
Yeah,
because we can always regenerate them and
we'll try it a few bits.
I think we'll have to try it out a couple
of times.
Mhm.
Okay, the 16, yeah.
Yeah,
I think that we should experiment with
that even. I don't know.
Yeah.
That's a good question to raise there.
Yes, that's up for experimentation,
I guess.
What does it look like in Dungeon
Settlers?
Mm.
Yeah,
I'd be interested to see what we come up
with.
Yeah, we'll have to,
we'll have to take a look in a few of
them, I'm not sure at the minute.
Yeah, cool, that's good.
Just wanted to raise that. We'll get the..
For you?
Yeah.
.
Yeah.
Of the recorders.
Yeah, it's a good one to raise,
that's still an open for now,
but we do need to generate stuff, so...
Yeah, that's um...
Yeah, interesting.
I know what you think.
You see this one here,
the art style is quite good though.
Because there's even, there's less,
No.
but there's more like, and what's this?
What's what?
for the donation settlers.
Yeah, this is just like,
you're walking through the dungeon and
it's kind of like...
No, they are so.
Ohh, sorry.
That's probably like 16.
Yeah, I think.
Maybe thirty-two.
And let me look at dungeon settlers.
Um...
Go bought that or something.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, 16 bit to 32 bit.
High bed style.
Yeah, the characters are 16.
Yeah. Okay, nice, nice, nice.
Cool, yeah, so yeah,
I'll make a note here.
You gotta look at the way Dungeon
Settlers.
have set up their characters too in terms
of pixel art and the presentation.
On the dark fantasy aspects, yeah,
last go June.
Tell you what there now,
I probably have to go,
you have to fix a few problems here now.
No problem, you're flat out today, well.
But that's flat out here,
but that's actually good.
I think we've got a lot of notes.
I'll capture this transcribe and then
I'll feed it in so you'll start seeing
uploads on the repo today.
And we'll go through everything and I'll
try to get it to answer all the questions.
But.
And then other questions,
if they're not important for now,
we can just.
We can leave them,
maybe it's not fully important.
You know what I mean?
I think it should be clear what we're
The.
trying to achieve with this game.
Cool.
Sound out you and I'm going to stop the
transcription there.
One second there now,
or actually I'll probably just end the
call in case,
just in case something happens with it.
Okay, yeah, cool.
Sure, sure, right, Ian, we chat here.
Hello, bye-bye.
Bye-bye.